Complex intonation, when in doubt, stress the noun. This is the beginning of an
extremely important part of spoken American English. The rhythms and
intonation patterns of the long streams of nouns and adjectives that are so commonly
used. These exercises will tie in the intonation patterns of adjectives, nice,
old, best, etc., Nouns, dog, house, surgeon, et cetera, and adverbs, very,
really, amazingly, et cetera. One way of approaching sentence intonation is not to
build each sentence from scratch. Instead, use patterns with each pattern similar to
a mathematical formula. Instead of plugging in numbers, however, plug in
words. It's important to note that there's a major difference between syllable stress
and compound In the syllable count exercises, each syllable was represented
by a single musical note. In the noun phrases, each individual word will be
represented by a single musical note, no matter how many total syllables there may
be. At times, what appears to be a single syllable word will have a longer sound to
it. Seed takes longer to say than seat, for example.